Guide to the Eugene O'Neill Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal Papers, 1872-1970; Series IV; 9.8; (27 boxes)
  - CARLOTTA MONTEREY O'NEILL DIARIES AND CALENDARS
    - Green "Daily Reminder"
      - Diary, 1929 (Box 83, Folder 1497)
      - Diary, 1930 (Box 83, Folder 1498)
      - Diary, 1931 (Box 83, Folder 1499)
      - Diary, 1932 (Box 84, Folder 1500)
      - Diary, 1933 (Box 84, Folder 1501)
      - Diary, 1934 (Box 84, Folder 1502)
      - Diary, 1935 (Box 84, Folder 1503)
      - Diary, 1936 (Box 85, Folder 1504)
      - Diary, 1937 (Box 85, Folder 1505)
      - Diary, 1938 (Box 85, Folder 1506)
      - Diary, 1939 (Box 85, Folder 1507)
      - Diary, 1940 (Box 86, Folder 1508)
      - Diary, 1941 (Box 86, Folder 1509)
      - Diary, 1942 (Box 86, Folder 1510)
      - Diary, 1943 (Box 86, Folder 1511)
    - French Relief Fund engagement calendar, 1944 (Box 87, Folder 1512)
      Only Jan 2-4 filled in.
    - Green "Daily Reminder", 1954 (Box 87, Folder 1513)
      O'Neill bookplate. For list of photographs pasted in, see: Appendix
    - "Bob, Inc." calendar, 1955 (Box 87, Folder 1514)
    - "Engagements", 1959 (Box 87, Folder 1515)
    - Red three-ring binder, 1959 (Box 87, Folder 1516)
    - Red three-ring binder, 1960 (Box 88, Folder 1517)
      Calorie chart laid in.
    - "Engagements", 1961 (Box 88, Folder 1518)
    - Red three-ring binder, 1962 (Box 88, Folder 1519)
      Diary pages laid in.
    - Red three-ring binder, 1963 (Box 89, Folder 1520)
    - "Engagements", 1964 (Box 89, Folder 1521)
      Calendar for 1962, but used for 1964.
      Only 1964 May 24-28 filled in.
  - CERTIFICATES AND AWARDS
    Arranged alphabetically by person and then by title.
    - Carlotta Monterey O'Neill
      - Medal from Dramatiska teatern (Stockholm, Sweden), 1962 May (Box 89, Folder 1522)
    - Eugene O'Neill
      - American Academy of Arts and Letters. Membership pin (medal attached to ribbon), in black case, 1933 Nov 9 (Box 89, Folder 1523)
      - American Philosophical Society. Certificate of membership, 1935 Apr 19
      - Antoinette Perry Award presented by the American Theatre Wing for Long Day's Journey Into Night. Silver medal, [1957] (Box 89, Folder 1524)
        i.e., Tony Award.
      - National Academy of Recording Arts and Sciences (U.S.). Plaque for nomination of Strange Interlude for best drama recording, 1963 (Box 89, Folder 1525)
      - National Institute of Arts and Letters (U.S.)
        - Certificate of membership, 1923 (Box 89, Folder 1526)
        - Gold medal in Tiffany and Company box, [1923] (Box 89, Folder 1527)
      - "New York Drama Critics Circle Award for the Best American Play, 1956-1957. Long Day's Journey Into Night by Eugene O'Neill." Certificate
      - Nobel Prize. Handpainted certificate in case, 1936 Dec 10
        See also: Series III, [Nobel Prize acceptance speech], box 76, folder 1418
        See also: Series IV, Clippings regarding Nobel Prize, box 93, folder 1599 through box 94, folder 1614
      - Pulitzer Prize certificates
        - Beyond the Horizon, 1920 Jun 2
        - Anna Christie, 1922 Jun 7
        - Strange Interlude, 1928 Jun 6
        - Long Day's Journey Into Night, 1957 May 6 (Box 89, Folder 1528)
      - United States. Post Office Dept. Certificate containing four $1 Eugene O'Neill stamps, 1967 Oct 16 (Box 89, Folder 1529)
        In portfolio stamped "Carlotta
        Monterey O'Neill."
      - Yale University. Honorary doctorate, 1926
  - CLIPPINGS AND EPHEMERA
    Folders contain clippings unless otherwise specified.
    Arranged alphabetically by name or title.
    - American Museum of Natural History. Museum shop book catalog, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1530)
    - Barton, Ralph, 1924-32 (Box 89, Folder 1531)
    - Boni & Liveright
      - Brochure for "The Works of Eugene O'Neill in Eight Volumes", [1928] (Box 89, Folder 1532)
      - Brochure for "The Works of Eugene O'Neill in Four Volumes" (3 copies), n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1533)
    - Boulton, Agnes, 1916-58, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1534)
    - Branchard, Katharina Ruede, 1937 (Box 89, Folder 1535)
    - Chaplin, Geraldine, 1962 Jan 3 (Box 89, Folder 1536)
    - Chaplin, Michael, 1965, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1537)
    - Chaplin, Oona Chaplin, Charlie, 1942-65 (Box 89, Folder 1538-1539)
    - Courvoisier Ltd. Brochure, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1540)
    - Dag Hammarskjöld, 1956-63, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1541-1542)
    - Eugene O'Neill Theater Center. Brochure, [1966] (Box 90, Folder 1543)
    - Jones, Robert Edmond Jones, 1954 (Box 90, Folder 1544)
    - Krutch, Joseph Wood, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1545)
    - Las Palmas (Canary Islands)
      - Tourism brochure, [1931] (Box 90, Folder 1546)
      - Packet of twelve tourism pictures, [1931] (Box 90, Folder 1547)
    - Liveright, Horace Brisbin, 1933 (Box 90, Folder 1548)
    - Macgowan, Kenneth, 1963 Apr 29 (Box 90, Folder 1549)
    - Nichols, Dudley, 1960 Jan 6 (Box 90, Folder 1550)
    - O'Neill, Carlotta Monterey
      - Clippings, 1924-25, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1551)
        Stored also in: Oversize, box 142,
        folder 2531
      - Dollar Steamship Line. First class ticket stub, 1929 Jan 2 (Box 90, Folder 1552)
      - Guadix (Spain). Picture cut from guide book, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 1553)
        Annotated by CMO: "Where the
        gypsies live - Spain."
      - National Wildlife Federation. Membership card, 1965 Mar (Box 90, Folder 1554)
      - Program for performance in The Man in Evening Clothes, 1924 Dec (Box 90, Folder 1555)
      - Program for performance in After Love - ?, 1925 Feb (Box 90, Folder 1556)
      - Programs for theater performances attended, 1960-65 (Box 90, Folder 1557-1558)
        For non-Eugene O'Neill plays.
      - Train ticket stubs and envelope for trip for two, New York to Seattle, [1936] (Box 90, Folder 1559)
    - O'Neill, Eugene
      - Biographical clippings, 1916-33 (Box 90, Folder 1560-1566)
      - Biographical clippings, 1934-52 (Box 91, Folder 1567-1579)
      - Biographical clippings, 1953-70 (Box 92, Folder 1580-1592)
      - Biographical clippings, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 1593-1598)
      - Clippings regarding Nobel Prize, 1936 (Box 93, Folder 1599-1607)
      - Clippings regarding Nobel Prize, 1936-43, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1608-1614)
      - Scrapbook of clippings of play reviews and of clippings about Eugene O'Neill, #1, 1915-20
      - Scrapbook of clippings of play reviews and of clippings about Eugene O'Neill, #2, 1921
      - Scrapbook of clippings of play reviews and of clippings about Eugene O'Neill, #3, 1920-22
    - O'Neill, Eugene, Jr. (Box 94, Folder 1615)
    - O'Neill, James
      - Scrapbook regarding The Dead Heart: A Story of the French Revolution by Watts Phillips, 1889-91 (Box 95, Folder 1616)
        Includes printed versions of play,
        notes by James O'Neill, programs,
        and souvenir of the play.
      - The Dead Heart: A Story of the French Revolution by Watts Phillips (London: Samuel French, 1889) (Box 96, Folder 1617)
        Printed version annotated by James
        O'Neill.
      - Charles Fechter's Acting Edition. Othello (London: W.R. Sams, 1861), 1914 (Box 96, Folder 1618)
        Presentation inscription from Frank
        Oakes Rose, 1914 May 21. Annotated,
        probably by Rose. On cover: "The
        property of Frank Oakes Rose.
        Presented to him by Charles Fechter
        Esqr., March 1874."
      - Prayer cards (five), n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1619)
      - Programs for James O'Neill's performances, 1872-1901, n.d.
      - Clippings of reviews of James O'Neill's acting, scrapbook #1, 1882-83 (Box 96, Folder 1620)
      - Clippings of reviews of James O'Neill's acting, scrapbook #2, 1885-87 (Box 97, Folder 1621)
      - Clippings of reviews of James O'Neill's acting, scrapbook #3, 1903, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1622)
      - Loose clippings, 1880-1937, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1623-1624)
      - A Sermon from Shakespeare: The Drama of Life by John Edgar Johnson (Philadelphia, [1902?]) (Box 98, Folder 1625)
      - Standard Recitations by Best Authors (New York: M.J. Ivers & Co., 1886) (Box 98, Folder 1626)
        Picture on cover of James O'Neill
        as Count of Monte Cristo. Includes
        note of explanation by CMO.
    - O'Neill, Mary Ellen Quinlan, 1922 (Box 98, Folder 1627)
    - O'Neill, Shane Rudraighe, 1936-61, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1628)
    - Pell, James H. G., n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1629)
    - Piel Craftsmen (Newburyport, Mass.). Brochure for ship models, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1630)
    - Provincetown Playhouse (New York, N.Y.). Brochure for Fashion, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1631)
    - Sao Paulo (Brazil) exhibition on Eugene O'Neill, 1959-60 (Box 98, Folder 1632-1635)
    - Student Theatre (New York, N.Y.). Brochure, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1636)
    - Sze, Sao-Ke Alfred, [1958] Jan 4 (Box 98, Folder 1637)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1961 Jun 18 (Box 98, Folder 1638)
    - Zenith Radio Corporation. Operating guides for portable radio, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1639)
  - FINANCIAL AND LEGAL MATERIAL
    Arranged alphabetically by name and then by title.
    - Carlotta Monterey O'Neill
      - L'Arche S.A. regarding French versions of all plays, 1962 May 18 (Box 99, Folder 1640)
      - Casa Genotta (Sea Island, Ga.). Legal documents and receipts regarding, 1931-37, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1641)
        folder 2534
      - Lincoln Repertory Company, Inc. regarding All God's Chillun and other plays, 1963 Jun 10 (Box 99, Folder 1642)
      - List of German productions, 1957-60 (Box 99, Folder 1643)
      - The Lowell, Apt. 5-A (28 E. 63rd Street, New York, N.Y.). Lease for, 1954 Oct 6 (Box 99, Folder 1644)
      - Manufacturers Trust Company
        - Cancelled checks, 1953-65 (Box 99, Folder 1645-1647)
        - Checkbooks containing check stubs and unused checks, 1955-57 (Box 99, Folder 1648-1652)
        - Checkbooks containing check stubs and unused checks, 1957-58 (Box 100, Folder 1653-1655)
        - Check stubs (loose), 1956 (Box 100, Folder 1656)
        - Statements, 1961-65 (Box 100, Folder 1657-1660)
          Includes cancelled checks.
        - Checkbooks containing unused checks, [196-?] (Box 100, Folder 1661-1662)
        - Checkbooks containing unused checks, [196-?] (Box 101, Folder 1663-1664)
      - Passports, 1927-31
        See: Series V, Photographs, box 111, folder 1977
        See: Series V, Photographs, box 111, folder 1987
        See: Series V, Photographs, box 111, folder 2002
      - Royalties from plays, holograph, in notebook, 1953-57 (Box 101, Folder 1665)
        Also includes medical expenses for
        EO, 1951-52.
      - Royalty and refund checks, 1963-64 (Box 101, Folder 1666)
      - Royalty statements for Italian productions, 1954-55
      - Royalty statements for plays
        - From Dramatists Play Service (New York, N.Y.), 1953-58 (Box 101, Folder 1667-1668)
        - From Random House (Firm), 1955-63, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1669-1672)
      - Shawmut Bank of Boston, N.A. Cancelled checks, 1953-54 (Box 101, Folder 1673)
      - Tao House (Danville, Calif.). Note for loan from Eugene O'Neill for building, 1941 Jan 3 (Box 101, Folder 1674)
        Includes note by CMO to Donald
        Clifford Gallup regarding loan.
      - Taxes. Notes regarding, 1958 (Box 101, Folder 1675)
      - Wills, 1954-64, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1676)
    - Eugene O'Neill
      - Contracts for plays
        - Richard G. Badger regarding Thirst and other plays, 1914 Mar 30 (photostat) (Box 102, Folder 1677)
          Annotated by EO: "(1914) (photostat
          of)." Includes clause from Richard
          G. Badger to Gotham Book Mart, 1924
          Jan 30 (photostat).
        - Rudolf Kommer regarding The Moon of the Caribbees and The Emperor Jones, 1923 May 3 (Box 102, Folder 1678)
        - Arvid Englind regarding Ile and other plays, 1924 Dec 12 (Box 102, Folder 1679)
        - Jonathan Cape Limited regarding The Emperor Jones and other plays, 1937 Jan 15 (Box 102, Folder 1680)
        - Argosy Corporation regarding The Moon of the Caribbees and other plays, 1940 Mar 30 (Box 102, Folder 1681)
        - Editorial Sudamericana regarding Nine Plays, 1945 Oct 16 (Box 102, Folder 1682)
        - S. Fischer Verlag regarding German translations of The Emperor Jones and other plays, 1951 Apr 16 (Box 102, Folder 1683)
        - S. Fischer Verlag regarding German translations of Ah, Wilderness! and other plays, 1951 Jun 25 (Box 102, Folder 1684)
      - Other
        - Account book showing income from play performances and book publications, holograph, in notebook, 1914-29 (Box 102, Folder 1685)
        - Account book showing income from book publications, holograph, in notebook, 1920-32 (Box 102, Folder 1686)
          Includes four loose pages.
        - Account book showing income from play performances, holograph, in notebook, 1927-35 (Box 102, Folder 1687)
        - Bill of sale to Carlotta Monterey O'Neill for Eugene O'Neill's possessions, 1932 Feb 9 (Box 102, Folder 1688)
        - Certificate of copyright registration for Thirst and Other One Act Plays from Library of Congress, 1914 (Box 102, Folder 1689)
        - Certificate of discharge as seaman from United States. Dept. of Commerce. Bureau of Navigation, 1911 Aug 19 (Box 102, Folder 1690)
          Includes note of explanation by
          CMO.
        - Legal document regarding moving picture of The Count of Monte Cristo, 1934 Nov 23 (Box 102, Folder 1691)
        - Notice regarding strictures on theatrical performances in Boston, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 1692)
        - Passport, 1930 Feb 26
          See: Series V, Photographs, box 108, folder 1868
    - Carlotta Monterey O'Neill and Eugene O'Neill
      - Check register from unidentified bank, 1949-50 (Box 102, Folder 1693)
      - Guaranty Trust Company of New York
        - Cancelled checks, 1931-47 (Box 102, Folder 1694-1700)
        - Cancelled checks, 1947-53 (Box 103, Folder 1701-1705)
        - Check registers, 1945-47 (Box 103, Folder 1706-1709)
      - Manufacturers Trust Company
        - Cancelled checks, 1945-53 (Box 103, Folder 1710)
        - Check stubs, 1946-50 (Box 103, Folder 1711-1715)
        - Blank checks, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1716)
      - Marriage documents, 1929 Jul (Box 104, Folder 1717)
        Includes one photograph of EO
        (another print in box 108, folder
        1868) and one photograph of CMO
        (another print in box 111, folder
        1995).
      - Merchants National Bank (Salem, Mass.). Cancelled checks, 1949-50 (Box 104, Folder 1718)
      - "Papers relative to our being residents of France"
        - General receipts, 1928-34 (Box 104, Folder 1719)
        - Lease for Château du Plessis, 1929 Jun 20 (Box 104, Folder 1720)
        - Receipts regarding car rental, 1929-30, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1721)
      - Royalty statements for plays, 1951-53 (Box 104, Folder 1722)
      - Shawmut Bank of Boston, N.A. Cancelled checks, 1951 (Box 104, Folder 1723)
      - Tax returns, 1952-53 (Box 104, Folder 1724)
    - James O'Neill; Mary Ellen Quinlan O'Neill
      - Marriage certificate, 1877 Jun 14 (Box 104, Folder 1725)
    - Mary Ellen Quinlan O'Neill
      - Birth record (copy), 1937 Nov 10 (Box 104, Folder 1726)
      - Inventory of property of estate of, typescript carbon, 1922 Aug 17 (Box 104, Folder 1727)
  - INSCRIPTIONS AND SIGNATURES
    Removed from books that belonged to Eugene O'Neill and
    Carlotta Monterey O'Neill. Arranged alphabetically by
    last name of inscriber.
    - Adams, Evangeline [Smith] to Eugene O'Neill, 1930 Aug 25 (Box 104, Folder 1728)
      From Astrology: Your Place Among the Stars by Evangeline Smith Adams (New
      York: Mead and Company, 1930).
    - Chase, Ilka to Eugene O'Neill and Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, 1948 Jul (Box 104, Folder 1729)
      From Free Admission by Ilka Chase
      (Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday and
      Company, Inc., 1948).
    - [Elkins], Felton to Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, 1939 (Box 104, Folder 1730)
      From The Last Flower: A Parable in Pictures by James Thurber (New York,
      London: Harper, 1939).
    - Gallup, Donald Clifford to Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, 1966 Jul 13 (Box 104, Folder 1731)
      Includes signature of CMO, New York,
      1964 Feb.
    - Hopkins, Arthur, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1732)
      From How's Your Second Act? by
      Arthur Hopkins (New York: Knopf,
      1919).
    - O'Neill, Carlotta Monterey
      - Note on O'Neill biographies, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1732a)
        From: The Poet's Quest by Richard
        Dana Skinner (New York, Toronto:
        Longman's, Green, 1935).
      - To Eugene O'Neill, 1929 Nov (Box 104, Folder 1733)
        From Peck's Bad Boy and His Pa by
        George W. Peck (Chicago: J.R.
        Stanton).
      - Signature, Château du Plessis, 1930 (Box 104, Folder 1734)
        From The Life and Mind of Emily Dickinson by Genevieve Taggard
        (New York, London: Alfred A. Knopf,
        1930).
      - Signature, New York, 1959 Apr 10 (Box 104, Folder 1735)
        From Composition of Foods,
        Agriculture Handbook No. 8 (U. S.
        Department of Agriculture).
      - Signature, New York, 1961 Aug (Box 104, Folder 1736)
        From Your Weight and Your Life by
        Alfred L. George (New York: Norton,
        1951).
    - O'Neill, Eugene
      - To Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, [1927] (Box 104, Folder 1737)
        From The Life of William Blake by Mona Wilson (London: The
        Nonesuch Press, 1927). Also signed
        by CMO, 1927.
      - Signature, Château du Plessis, [19]29 (Box 104, Folder 1738)
        From The Dramas of Sophocles translated by George Young (London:
        Dent, New York: Dutton, [1928]).
      - Signature, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1739)
        From Fir Flower Tablets, English
        version by Amy Lowell (1921).
    - Shyre, Paul to Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, 1961 Jun 5 (Box 104, Folder 1740)
      From Elsa by Joy Adamson (New York:
      Pantheon, 1961).
    - Skinner, Richard Dana to Eugene O'Neill, 1934 (Box 104, Folder 1741)
      From Two Years Before the Mast: A Personal Narrative of Life at Sea by
      Richard Henry Dana (New York: Harper
      & Brothers, 1841). Includes title
      page.
    - Ward, Robert L.
      - To Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, 1957 Dec 24 (Box 104, Folder 1742)
        From Diseases of the Skin by
        George C. Andrews (Philadelphia,
        London: Saunders, 1932).
      - To Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, 1959 Dec (Box 104, Folder 1743)
        From Blakiston's New Gould Medical Dictionary (Philadelphia, Toronto,
        1949).
      - To Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1744)
        From A Textbook of Medicine by
        Russell L. Cecil (Philadelphia:
        Saunders, 1943).
    - Winther, Sophus Keith to Eugene O'Neill and Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, 1943 Sep (Box 104, Folder 1745)
      From The Penthouse Theatre: Its History and Technique by Glenn
      Hughes (New York, Los Angeles: S.
      French, 1942). Also includes
      inscription from Glenn Hughes to
      Sophus Keith Winther and Eline
      Winther, 1942 May.
    - Young, Stark to Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, 1929 Jun (Box 104, Folder 1746)
      From The Three Fountains by Stark
      Young (New York: Scribner's Sons,
      1927).
    - Unidentified to Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, 1958 Aug 18 (Box 104, Folder 1747)
      From Shakespeare of London by
      Marchette Gaylord Chute (New York:
      Dutton, 1957).
  - MEDICAL INFORMATION
    Arranged alphabetically by last name and then
    chronologically.
    - Carlotta Monterey O'Neill
      - Welton, Jean M., R.N. "Daily Medical Record of Mrs. Eugene O'Neill," holograph
        - Book 1, Mar 1-Aug 24, 1954 (Box 104, Folder 1748)
        - Book 2, Aug 25-Oct 9, 1954 (Box 104, Folder 1749)
      - Welton, Jean M., R.N. "Nurse's Notes," holograph, in notebook, 1956 (Box 104, Folder 1750)
        Full dates: 1956 May 28-Jun 20.
      - Heart rate results, 1963 May 17 (Box 104, Folder 1751)
      - Notes regarding medication taken, in notebook, 1963 Nov (Box 104, Folder 1752)
        In CMO's hand.
      - Information regarding nutrition, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1753)
      - Nurses at Presbyterian Hospital (New York, N.Y.). List, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1754)
    - Eugene O'Neill
      - Nurses' record, 1946 (Box 105, Folder 1755)
      - Illness. Notes by Jean M. Welton and Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, 1951-53 (Box 105, Folder 1756)
        See also: Series IV, Royalties from plays, holograph, in notebook, box 101, folder 1665
      - Medical record kept by Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, Jean M. Welton, Harry L. Kozol, and others
        - First book, 1951 Jun-52 Jan (Box 105, Folder 1757)
        - Vol. I, 1952 Jan-Mar (Box 105, Folder 1758)
        - Vol. II, 1952 Mar-May (Box 105, Folder 1759)
        - Vol. III, 1952 May-Jul (Box 105, Folder 1760)
        - Vol. IV, 1952 Aug-Oct (Box 105, Folder 1761)
        - Vol. V, 1952 Oct-Dec (Box 105, Folder 1762)
        - Vol. VI, 1952 Dec-53 Feb (Box 105, Folder 1763)
        - Vol. VII, 1953 Feb-Apr (Box 105, Folder 1764)
        - Vol. VIII, 1953 Apr-Jun (Box 105, Folder 1765)
        - Vol. IX, 1953 Jun-Jul (Box 105, Folder 1766)
        - Vol. X, 1953 Aug-Sep (Box 105, Folder 1767)
        - Vol. XI, 1953 Sep-Oct (Box 106, Folder 1768)
        - Vol. XII, 1953 Oct-Nov (Box 106, Folder 1769)
        - Vol. XIII, 1953 Nov (Box 106, Folder 1770)
      - Autopsy report (2 copies, typescript and carbon), 1953 Nov 28 (Box 106, Folder 1771)
        Includes note of permission from CMO,
        1953 Nov 27.
      - Death certificate (certified copy), 1954 Apr 7 (Box 106, Folder 1772)
        Includes note, holograph, from CMO to
        Donald Clifford Gallup, 1955 Jul 15.
      - "Tolserol," holograph, in notebook, n.y. Jul-Aug (Box 106, Folder 1773)
        List of dates taken. Annotated on
        cover in CMO's hand: "Carlotta
        Monterey O'Neill, Boston, 1954."
  - PERSONAL WRITINGS AND NOTES
    Arranged alphabetically by last name and then by title.
    - Carlotta Monterey O'Neill
      - Appointments. Notes regarding, holograph, 1966, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1774)
      - Christmas lists, 1963, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1775)
      - Envelopes inscribed with miscellaneous notes, 1945-56, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1776)
      - Gierow, Karl Ragnar. Account of meeting with, typescript carbon, corrected, 1959 Apr 25 (Box 106, Folder 1777)
      - Long Day's Journey Into Night. Comments on, drafts, typescript and carbon (Box 106, Folder 1778)
      - "'Notes' Dictated to me by Gene," typescript, corrected, signed, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1779)
      - Regarding Eugene O'Neill
        - Chronology of his life, 1908-1917, notes, holograph, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1780)
        - Excerpt from letter from Eugene O'Neill to Arthur Hobson Quinn, drafts, typescript and carbon (Box 106, Folder 1781)
        - First meeting and later life, notes, holograph, and drafts, typescript and carbon (Box 106, Folder 1782)
        - His manner of receiving guests, drafts, typescript and carbon, 1959 Jan 1 (Box 106, Folder 1783)
        - Impact of move from Tao House (Danville, Calif.) to San Francisco, draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1959 Mar 28 (Box 106, Folder 1784)
        - List of manuscripts sent to institutions, draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1785)
        - Searching for an apartment in San Francisco (Calif.), draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1959 Apr 4 (Box 106, Folder 1786)
      - Poems by Eugene O'Neill copied by Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, in volume, holograph, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1787)
      - Poems by others copied by Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, holograph and typescript, 1953, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1788)
      - Signatures (four), 1953, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1789)
        Three on notebook covers; one on
        diary front page.